Guide to the records of the Musical Acoustics Research Library (MARL) M1711
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 3. Arthur H. Benade Collection, 1956-1987; 19.182 Linear Feet; Between 1982 and late 1987: After cancer was diagnosed in the fall of 1982, Benade made increased use of detailed projections (with many pages hand-drawn) for many of his lectures. Though casual in appearance, these were planned
  - Writings - A Comment on the Acoustical Relationship Between the Vienna and Conservatory System Oboes. Written for Hans Hadamowsky's instruction book on the Vienna oboe. Unpublished, (typescript 1 p. and letters), 1974 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Writings - "Identification of the Separate Tones Heard in a Woodwind Multiphonic Sound as Grouped Subsets of its Spectral Components," with L. J. Livingston. J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 55:S49 (reprint of abstr.; handwritten notes 2pp.), 1974 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.1919771
  - Writings - "Mechanism of Multiphonic Tone Production in Woodwinds," J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 55:S49 (reprint of abstr.; handwritten notes, 2pp.), 1974 (Box 104, Folder 4)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.1919772
  - Writings - "Nonlinear Aspects of Wind Instrument Regeneration," J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 55:S69, (annotated abstract, reprint; handwritten notes, 2pp.), 1974; On the abstract Benade wrote, "AHB's 10-year retrospective." It took Benade ten years of work to be able to write that abstract and know it was true. (Box 104, Folder 5)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.1919870
  - Writings - The Physics of Woodwinds. Colloquium talk, Princeton University, 7 February. Unpublished, (handwritten outline, 6pp.; slides mentioned in talk are missing.), 1974 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Writings - "On Plane and Spherical Waves in Horns with Nonuniform Flare, I: Theory of Radiation, Resonance Frequencies and Mode Conversion," with E. V. Jansson. Acustica 31(2):79-98; and "On Plane and Spherical Waves in Horns with Nonuniform Flare, II: Prediction and Measurements of Resonance Frequencies and Radiation Losses," with E. V. Jansson. Acustica 31(4):185-202 (typescript, 38 pp.), 1974 (Box 104, Folder 7)
    Preprint, and reprint
    Preprint, published as a single volume in 1973 by the Speech Transmission Laboratory, Royal Institute of Technology (KTH), Stockholm, Sweden. Reprinted in Musical Acoustics: Piano and Wind Instruments, Earle L. Kent, ed., Benchmark Papers in Acoustics, Dowden, Hutchinson, & Ross, Stroudsburg, PA (1977).
  - Writings - On Reeds and Facings. Colloquium talk, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 5 December. Unpublished, (handwritten notes, 4pp.), 1974 (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Writings - Wind Instruments Seminar. Outlines and handouts for a weekly series given September-December at the University of Michigan School of Music, (handwritten notes, 48 pp.), 1974 (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Writings - "Some Musically Oriented Acoustics Demonstrations," J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 57:S20 (reprint of abstr.; handwritten notes, 3pp.), 1975 (Box 104, Folder 10)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.1995114
  - Writings - "The Wolf Tone on Violin Family Instruments," Catgut Acoust. Soc. Newsletter 24:21-23, November, (reprint, 4 pp.), 1975 (Box 104, Folder 11)
    Reprinted in Research Papers in Violin Acoustics 1975-1993, Carleen Maley Hutchins, ed., Acoustical Society of America (1995), 1:117-120.
  - Writings - "The Path from String to Ear," Catgut Acoust. Soc. Newsletter 25:5, May, (reprint of abstr.; handwritten notes, 1p.), 1976 (Box 104, Folder 12)
  - Writings - "Wind Instrument Final Adjustment Procedures," J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 59:S50-51 (reprint of abstr.; handwritten notes, 5pp.), 1976 (Box 104, Folder 13)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2002740
  - Writings - Review of Sound Structure in Music, by Robert Erickson, J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 60(5):1236, (reprint, 1 p.), 1976 (Box 104, Folder 14)
  - Writings - Acoustical Evolution of Wind Instruments. Course notes and detailed class handout sheets. Unpublished, (typescripts, 84 pp.), 1977 (Box 104, Folder 15)
  - Writings - Analysis of Violin Resonance Measurement Techniques, with an introduction plus three related papers: 1) On the Use of a Drive Line Between Driver Coil and a Fiddle Bridge (26 July 1977), 2) On Electrodynamic Driving of a Vibration Experiment, (26 July 1977), and 3) On Fiddle String Resonances and their Excitation (21 September 1977) (typescripts, 11 pp.) (Box 104, Folder 16)
  - Writings - "The Effects of Reed Resonance on Woodwind Tone Production," with S. C. Thompson. J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 61:S35 (reprint of abstr.), 1977 (Box 104, Folder 17)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2015600
  - Writings - "Fiddle Acoustics: The Summer of 1977," Catgut Acoust. Soc. Newsletter 28:3-6, November, (reprint, 4 pp.) (Box 104, Folder 18)
  - Writings - "How to Test a Good Trumpet," The Instrumentalist 31(8):57-58 (reprint, 2 pp.), 1977 (Box 104, Folder 19)
  - Writings - Musical Acoustics Today: A scientific Crossroads. Plenary Session Lecture, 9th International Congress on Acoustics, Madrid, July. In Proceedings, 9th International Congress on Acoustics, Madrid 4-9 July (typescript, pp. 81-91), 1977 (Box 104, Folder 20)
  - Writings - "The Room Around the Instrument," Catgut Acoust. Soc. Newsletter 28:9-10, November, (typescript 2pp.)., 1977; Summary and extension of a talk presented at the International Symposium on Violin Acoustics, Cambridge England, June 27-July 1, 1977. (Box 104, Folder 21)
  - Writings - "Violin Stringing and Leopold Mozart's Advice," Catgut Acoust. Soc. Newsletter 28:7-9, November. Talk presented at the International Symposium on Violin Acoustics, Cambridge England, June 27-July 1, (reprint of abstr.; typescript of talk, 2 pp.), 1977 (Box 104, Folder 22)
  - Writings - "Wind Instrument Very-Nearfield and Room-Average Spectra," with P. S. Greenberg, P. L. Hoekje, and R. M. Suttle. J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 61:S35, (reprint of abstr.; handwritten notes and figs. 9pp.), 1977 (Box 104, Folder 23)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2015601
  - Writings - Acoustical Studies of Wind Instruments. NSF Proposal with a description of the current status of Benade's research and lab activities. Unpublished, (typescript, 51 pp.), 1978 (Box 104, Folder 24)
  - Writings - "Room Acoustic Requirements for the Performer," J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 63:S36 (reprint of abstr.; handwritten notes and figs. 14 pp.), 1978 (Box 104, Folder 25)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2016619
  - Writings - "Wave Propagation in Strongly Curved Musical Instrument Tubes," with D. Keefe and G. McCracken. J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 63:S57 (reprint of abstr.), 1978 (Box 104, Folder 26)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2016724
  - Writings - When a Player of Modern Woodwinds Meets an Earlier Version of his Instrument. Letter to Isobel Ward, 3 October. Unpublished, (typescript, 3pp.), 1978; The writing deals especially with the oboe, but is of general applicability. This is one of several letters Benade wrote to which he gave special treatment. He put a title on it and shared it generously. (Box 104, Folder 27)
  - Writings - The 'Chops' Letter: How to Make Friends with an Unfamiliar Clarinet, 4 January. Letter to George Plasko. Unpublished, (typescript, 4 pp.), 1979 (Box 104, Folder 28)
  - Writings - "Measured Reproducibility of Clarinet Spectra," with C. O. Larson. J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 66:S30, (reprint of abstr.), 1979 (Box 104, Folder 29)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2017706
  - Writings - On the Capillary Method of Impedance Measurement--A Brief Note. Letter to Xavier Lurton, 11 May. Unpublished, (typescript, 2 pp.), 1979 (Box 104, Folder 30)
  - Writings - "Organ Reed and Air Column Regenerative Relations: Tools of the Voicer's Trade," J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 66:S67 (reprint of abstr.; handwritten notes and figs., 11pp.), 1979 (Box 104, Folder 31)
  - Writings - Reeds for Baroque Oboes, Effects of Wall Materials, and Reed Cavity and Neck Requirements--Some Brief Notes. Letter to Nora Post,1 March. Unpublished, (typescript, 3 pp.), 1979 (Box 104, Folder 32)
  - Writings - "Wind Instruments," in The New Grove Dictionary of Music and Musicians, Acoustics: IV, 1:77-82, Grove, London, (photocopies, 6 pp.), 1980 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Writings - "Clarinet Perturbation Weight Function Measurements," with J. C. Carma. J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 68:S111, 21 November 1980, (reprint of abstr.; typescript of talk, 19 pp. ) (Box 105, Folder 2)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2004555
  - Writings - An Exhibition of Flutes in Honor of Dayton C. Miller and in Honor of the Centenary of Case Institute of Technology. Catalog of exhibit at the Western Reserve Historical Society, Cleveland, OH, (5-17 October). Introduction; essay: "A Brief History of the Flute." Photos of and Commentary on the 13 Flutes Exhibited--5 from the D. C. Miller Collection, U.S. Library of Congress; 7 from the A. H. Benade Collection; and 1 on anonymous loan, (catalogue, 20 pp.), 1980 (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Writings - "Impedance Measurement Source and Microphone Proximity Effects," with D. H. Keefe. J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 68:S111, 21 November, (reprint of abstr. and typescript of paper 25 pp.), 1980 (Box 105, Folder 4)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2004556
  - Writings - "John Schelleng in Retrospect," J. Catgut Acoust. Soc. 33:3, May, (reprint of abstract, 1 p.], 1980 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Writings - "Musical Spectrum and Transfer Function Measurements: Techniques, Pitfalls, Interpretation," invited paper, J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 67:S97-98, 25 April, (original speaker's notes, handwritten 5pp., slides, and reprint of abstr.), 1980; 6 slides, see light media: box 59, folder 3 (Box 105, Folder 6)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2018510
  - Writings - "News from Cleveland," J. Catgut Acoust. Soc. 33:6, May, (reprint of abstract,1 p.), 1980 (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - Writings - Sketchy Notes on Second-Order Effects in Loudspeakers. Unpublished, (typescript 2 pp.), 1980 (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Writings - "Source Strength Relations for the Boehm Flute," J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 67:S84-85, 25 April, (reprint of abstr., 2 pp.), 1980; 13 slides, see light media: box 59, folder 4 (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Writings - "Spectrum Transformation Properties of the Clarinet and Saxophone," with D. H. Keefe, J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 67:S98, 25 April, (reprint of abstr. plus 11 figs.), 1980 (Box 105, Folder 10)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2018512
  - Writings - Summary of Work in Progress, Prepared for National Science Foundation Grant Continuation Report. Unpublished, (typescript, 17 pp.), 1980 (Box 105, Folder 11)
  - Writings - "Trumpet Spectrum Transformation Systematics," with P. L. Hoekje, J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 67:S85, 25 April, (reprint of abstr.), 1980 (Box 105, Folder 12)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2018438
  - Writings - Wind Instruments and Music Acoustics. Three lectures given at a conference in Stockholm and published in Sound Generation in Winds, Strings, Computers, 1979, Stockholm, Publication 29, Royal Swedish Academy of Music, Stockholm pp. 14-99. Titles of the three talks are 1) "Sound Production in Wind Instruments," 2) "Sound Radiation from Instruments," and 3) "Instrument Sounds in a Room," (typescript, 86 pp.), 1979-1980 (Box 105, Folder 13)
  - Writings - Appendix to two papers, see below, on spectrum Systematics. Unpublished, (typescript, 4 pp.). 1) "Bassoon Spectrum Transformation Function," with J. C. Carman and P. H. Barrett, J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 69:S37, 20 May, (reprint of abstr. plus 4 typed pp.); 2) "Spectral Similarities of Tones from 'Especially Useful' Musical Instruments, J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 69:S37, 20 May, (reprint of abstr. plus 4-page typed summary, 9 figs.), 1981 (Box 105, Folder 14)
  - Writings - Boehm's Acoustics After 100 Years, Theobald Boehm Centenary Lecture, National Flute Association Annual Convention, Detroit, MI, 22 August. Unpublished, (typescript 4 pp.), 1981; 4 slides in light media: box 59 fold.6 (Box 105, Folder 15)
  - Writings - "Brass Wind Instrument Impulse Response Measurements," with J. H. Smith. J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 70:S22-23,1 December, (reprint of abstr. plus 3 pp. typed notes, 7 figs.), 1981 (Box 105, Folder 16)
  - Writings - "Clarinet Register-Hole Experiments," American Association of Physics Teachers, New York meeting, AAPT Announcer 10(4):93, 28 January, (abstr.and unpublished outline, 2 pp.), 1981 (Box 105, Folder 17)
  - Writings - "Impedance Measurement Source and Microphone Proximity Effects," with D. H. Keefe. J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 69(5):1489-1495, (reprint, 7 pp.), 1981 (Box 105, Folder 18)
  - Writings - King Talks with the Experts: Arthur H. Benade, (transcript of taped discussion at King Band Instrument Company, Eastlake, OH, July; xerox of proposed dealer's pamphlet 8 pp.), 1981 (Box 105, Folder 19)
  - Writings - Microphones, Loudspeakers, and Rooms. Talk for a Case Western Reserve University recruiting seminar, 28 September. Unpublished, (handwritten notes and acetates, 7 pp.), 1981 (Box 105, Folder 20)
  - Writings - "Musical Instruments," entry in the American Institute of Physics Encyclopedia of Physics, Rita G. Lerner and George L. Trigg, eds., Addison Wesley, Reading, MA, pp. 641-644, (photocopies, 4 pp.); "News from Cleveland," J. Catgut Acoust. Soc. 36:3, November, (typescript, 1 p.), 1981 (Box 105, Folder 21)
  - Writings - The NX Group: 1) The Physics of a New Clarinet. Colloquium talk, SUNY-Albany, 20 October. Unpublished, (speaker's notes, figures, and 35-mm slides,11 pp.); 2) and 3) The Physics of a New Clarinet. Colloquium talks, University of Victoria, BC,12 March 1982, and University of British Columbia, Vancouver, B.C.,11 March 198. Unpublished, (typescript, the identical set of a cover sheet and acetates was used at both presentations, with details adapted to two different audiences,10 pp.); 4) The Physics of a New Clarinet. Colloquium talk, MIT, Department of Mechanical Engineering,11 February 1983. Unpublished, (abstract, speaker's notes, and acetates,17 pp.); 5) The Physics of a New Clarinet Design. Colloquium talk, Case Western Reserve University, Physics Department, 7 April 1983. Unpublished, (typescript announcement and projected figures, 9 pp.); 6) "Musical/Acoustical Design of the NX Clarinet," J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 73:S84,13 May 1983. (paper projections, same set as CWRU presentation plus more,15 pp.); 7)The Musical Physics of a New Clarinet Design. Colloquium talk, Oberlin College,16 September 1983. Unpublished, (typescript of announcement; notes and acetate projections,6 pp.); 8) "Benade's NX Clarinet: Its genesis" The Clarinet ,published in February/March 1994, written in 1987, (journal article, 3 pp.); 9) "The Physics of a New Clarinet Design," with Douglas H. Keefe. Galpin Soc. J., 49, March 1996, pp. 113-142, (not included), 1981-1996 (Box 105, Folder 22)
    For talk 5) The Physics of a New Clarinet Design: Please note that changes were made, via cut and paste, in Figs. 1, 2, and 4 for this talk, and then used in the similar talks that followed. For article "Benade's NX Clarinet: Its genesis," see also a related paper by George Jameson—"Benade's NX Clarinet: Mechanical and Other Considerations," The Clarinet (May/June 1994), pp. 32-33. This provides some design details not included in Benade's February/March 1994 article. For article "The Physics of a New Clarinet Design," the middle section of three is by Benade, dictated to his wife in 1987. The outer sections clarify points in the central section, sometimes taking issue with them. Keefe also provides Conclusions and an Appendix on recent research on sound production in the clarinet. Benade requested that Keefe be asked to prepare the dictated notes (written near the end of his illness) as a submission suitable for the G.S.J. [30 pp.]
  - Writings - "Oboe and Bassoon Perturbation Weight Function Measurements," with J. C. Carman. J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 70, S23, (abstr. and unpublished speaker's notes and acetates, 21 pp.), 1981 (Box 105, Folder 23)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2018770
  - Writings - "Oboe Normal Mode Adjustment Via Reed-Staple Proportioning," with W. B. Richards. J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 69:S37 (abstr. see paper with nearly same title and slightly different abstract published in 1983)., 1981 (Box 105, Folder 24)
  - Writings - Player! Mouthpiece! Neck! Reed! Getting Them All to Cooperate. Talk, North American Saxophone Alliance national convention, Tempe, AZ,14 March. Unpublished, (abstract, speaker's notes,10 pp. and four 35-mm slides), 1981 (Box 105, Folder 25)
  - Writings - Response of a Cone to a Flow Impulse at its Small End. July/August. Unpublished, (handwritten notes, 4 pp.), 1981 (Box 105, Folder 26)
  - Writings - "Spectral Similarities of Tones from 'Especially Useful' Musical Instruments," J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 69:S37, 20 May, (abstr. plus 4-page typed summary, 9 figs. See also Appendix to two papers, 1981). (Box 105, Folder 27)
  - Writings - Wall Vibration and Boundary Layer Effects in Wind Instruments. Colloquium talk, University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, IL, 13 November. Unpublished, (cover sheet, speaker's notes, and transparencies,14 pp.), 1981 (Box 105, Folder 28)
  - Writings - Energy Absorption Effects in Vibrating Systems. Lecture, Clevite Corporation, Cleveland, OH. 23 November. Unpublished, (handwritten outline,12 pp.), 1982 (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - Writings - "Impedance and Impulse Response Measurements Using Low-Cost Components," with M. I. Ibisi. J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 72:S63, (handwritten notes and acetates for talk, 11 pp.), 1982 (Box 106, Folder 2)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2019992
  - Writings - "Measurement of Room-Averaged Spectra from Complex Sources," J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 72:S63 (abstr. with corrections and unpublished speaker's notes and acetates, 14 pp.), 1982 (Box 106, Folder 3)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2019990
  - Writings - Music: From Player to Listener Via Instrument and Room. Annual Sigma Pi Sigma, Society of Physics Students; lecture, Physics Department, California State University, Sacramento,15 April. Unpublished, (posting and speaker's notes 4 pp.), 1982 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Writings - "Obituary for Robert S. Shankland." J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 72(4), 1335 (1 p.), 1982 (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - Writings - On the Other Wave Equation. Colloquium talk, Case Western Reserve University. Unpublished, (1 Cover sheet and transparencies,14 pp.), 1982 (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Writings - Present Status and Major Questions in Musical Acoustics. Talk for the American Association of Physics Teachers, Northern California Section, Sacramento, CA. Unpublished, (abstract and acetates, 17 pp.), 1982 (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - Writings - "Second-Harmonic Sound Generation at Woodwind Tone Holes," with W. B. Richards J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 71:S91, 29 April, (typescript 33 pp.), 1982; Richards, a physics professor at Oberlin College, did this work during a sabbatical at Benade's lab. It was reported on in talks at Case Western Reserve and an Acoustical Society meeting. Because the results were preliminary and Richards did not have the equipment at Oberlin to verify the results the paper was never published, except the abstract. (Box 106, Folder 8)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2019631
  - Writings - "Sitar Spectrum Properties," with W. G. Messenger. J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 71:S83, 29 April, (abstr. and unpublished acetates,13 pp.), 1982 (Box 106, Folder 9)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2019587
  - Writings - "Vocal Tract Effects in Wind Instrument Regeneration," with P. L. Hoekje. J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 71:S91, 29 April, (abstr. and unpublished acetates,11 pp.), 1982 (Box 106, Folder 10)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2019632
  - Writings - "Volume Perturbers as Possible Sound Field Randomizers in Room-Average Spectrum Measurement Procedures," with I. M. Lindevald. J. Acoust. Soc. Am. 72:S63-64,11 November, (abstr. and unpublished speaker's notes, equations, and figures,15 pp.), 1982 (Box 106, Folder 11)
    Abstract online: http://dx.doi.org/10.1121/1.2019995
  - Writings - What is a Really Good Wind Instrument? Colloquium talk, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, 11 March 1982. Unpublished, (cover sheet and acetates, 8 pp.) (Box 106, Folder 12)
  - Writings - Woodwind Instruments as a Problem in Lattice Dynamics. Colloquium talk, Simon Fraser University, Vancouver, BC, 10 March. Unpublished, (cover sheet and acetates,10 pp.), 1982 (Box 106, Folder 13)
  - Writings - The Woodwind History Group: 1) Historical Evolution of Wind Instruments. Informal talk, California State University, Sacramento,14 April 1982. Unpublished, (speaker's notes, 3 pp.); 2) Woodwinds: The Technical-Musical Path Since 1700. Colloquium talk to physics and music departments, New York University,1982. Unpublished, (abstract and set of projected paper and acetate pages, 23 pp.); 3) Dechové Nástroje: Techniký a Hudební Vývoj od Roku 1700. Published in 3 parts. Hudební Nástroje, 21(1), 21(2), and 21(3),1984. Czech translation of the 1982 talk Woodwinds: The Technical-Musical Path Since 1700, (journal pages, 3 pp.); 4) Woodwinds: The Evolutionary Path Since 1700, (1984). Unpublished, (typescript with figures and references, 42 pp. reduced to 21); 5) "The Evolution of Woodwinds," The Gamut 14:10-33 (1985), "a quarterly of ideas" published by Cleveland State University, (not included); 6) Woodwinds: The Evolutionary Path Since 1700. Talk for the 12th Int. Congress on Acoustics, Toronto, 24-31 July 1986, paper K6-3, 31 July 1986, (2-page summary published in Proceedings and unpublished cover sheet, speaker's notes, 11 slides, and acetates, 29 pp.); 7) "Woodwinds: the Evolutionary Path since 1770," with Douglas H. Keefe. The Galpin Society Journal, XLVII, 63-114, March 1994, (62 pp., original, unabridge typescript included), 1982-1994; About 4) Woodwinds: The Evolutionary Path Since 1700, (1984). The typescript, submitted to a local academic journal, led to a reduced and rewritten result by others. The same typescript formed a basis for a longer article that appeared in 1994 in The Galpin Society Journal (see 5) and 7) below). About 7) the Woodwinds article published in the Galpin Society Journal: Benade during his illness realized that his 1984 typescript could, with only a little work, be made appropriate for submission to the Galpin Society for publication. He suggested that his former student, Doug Keefe, be asked if he might want to help with this article and also with a write-up on the NX clarinet. Doug expanded it considerably, and included his mentor as co-editor. Benade, member of the Galpin Society for many years, was asked to submit some of his writing for the Journal. (Box 106, Folder 14)
  - Writings - "Air Column, Reed, and Player's Windway Interactions in Musical Instruments," invited paper, University of Iowa Conference on the Biophysics of Voice Production, 7 May 1983, in Vocal Fold Physiology: Biomechanism, Acoustics and Phonatory Control, I. R. Titze and R. C. Scherer, eds., Denver Center for the Performing Arts, Denver (1985), pp 425-452, with transcription of short discussion following the talk, (photocopies of book, 28 pp.) The original typescript of this article also appears in Akustická Konference: Akustické Technické Aspekty Hudebních Nástroju, Kraslice 1983, Hradec Králové, Czechoslovakia (1983), pp. 113-168. [56 pp.]., Vocal Fold Physiology Conference (1983: Iwoa City, Iowa). Vocal Physiology: Biomechanics, Acoustics and Phonatory Control, edited by Ingo R. Titze and Ronald C. Scherer. Book donated by Virginia Benade, see Music Library stacks. (Box 106, Folder 15)